With the rise of pop music, jazz, and electronic music, both opera and classical music started to fade away from the public eye.
随着流行音乐、爵士乐和电子音乐的兴起，歌剧和古典音乐都开始淡出公众视野。
Some people are beginning to wonder whether opera and classical music are still relevant to the modern world of music.
一些人开始怀疑，歌剧和古典音乐对现代乐坛是否仍有现实意义。
Granted, you will not typically see today’s teenagers lending their ears to Bach anytime soon, but there are some major indicators that both opera and classical music are now still quite alive.
诚然，短期内你一般不会看到如今的青少年去聆听巴赫，但有一些重要迹象表明，歌剧和古典音乐如今都依然颇具活力。
The most significant indicator of classical music’s importance in society today is the fact that much of the popular music that is currently being produced uses similar beats, harmonies, and melodies to those that were used in some of classical music’s best works.
古典音乐在当今社会的重要性，最显著的迹象就是这样一个事实：当下制作的很多流行音乐，所用的节拍、和声与旋律都与古典音乐中某些最优秀作品里的相似。
Even so, it can be difficult for those who do not study music theory to see this as an indicator, since it is subtle and just shows the impact symphonic orchestras have had on society’s taste in music.
即便如此，不学乐理的人可能很难把这一点看作一种迹象，因为它不易察觉，只是体现出交响乐团对社会大众的音乐品味所产生的影响。
A better example of the relevance of opera and classical music can be seen in the invention of the rock opera.
摇滚歌剧的发明就是一个更好的例子，能说明歌剧和古典音乐的现实意义。
Opera, in its simplest definition, is telling a story using music as its form.
按最简单的定义来说，歌剧就是以音乐为形式来讲述故事。
The art of telling a story using music has not faded in the least.
用音乐讲述故事这门艺术丝毫没有衰落。
In fact, sometimes actual orchestras are used for major parts of the opera itself.
事实上，摇滚歌剧本身的主要部分有时会用到真正的管弦乐团。
Some of the world’s greatest hits have been parts of rock operas.
世界上一些最热门的歌曲就出自摇滚歌剧。
Fans of classical music can also tell you that there are few types of music that are more expressive.
古典音乐的爱好者也能告诉你，比古典音乐更富表现力的音乐类型寥寥无几。
So, it should come as no surprise to anyone that classical music pieces are still used as background music in modern movies.
所以，古典乐曲仍在现代电影中用作背景音乐，这应该不会让任何人感到意外。
Symphonic orchestra compositions have also been created solely for the purpose of being included in major motion pictures.
还有一些交响管弦乐作品，纯粹是为了用在大制作电影中而创作的。
These are often very well received amongst mainstream music fans.
这些作品在主流音乐爱好者中往往很受欢迎。
Classical music and opera are the very foundation upon which our modern music is based.
古典音乐和歌剧正是我们现代音乐赖以建立的基础。
Considering the huge impact they have had on our current society, there is no doubt that we can expect them to continue to remain important for centuries to come.
考虑到它们对我们当今社会产生的巨大影响，毫无疑问，我们可以预期它们在未来几个世纪里会继续保持重要地位。